{"posts":[{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"tuts and labs","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"week 01","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"tutorial 01 - introduction to git and python basics","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"i got a error code 500 problem when i tried to import the files of lab01 idk wot to do with it. i'm worried about the time.","answers":[{"text":"our webapp had some issues for a short period. the webapp is up and running again. please try now.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"tuts and labs","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"week 01","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"tutorial 01 - introduction to git and python basics","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"i'm unable to push because updates were rejected because the tip of your current branch is behind its remote counterpart . here's the full error message i have no clue what i'm doing wrong help would be greatly appreciated. i'm using a public repo as my education account still hasn't been approved.","answers":[{"text":"if you read the hints the messages would suggest that remotely on github the branch is ahead of your local machine's branch. what you would need to do is git pull to update your local machine branch to get it up to date before pushing any changes local- gt remote. it is honestly recommended to regularly pull to keep up-to-date with remote. this becomes very important in your future group project.","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thanks. sorry if this is stupid but i'm not sure how to specify the branch as simply typing git pull doesn't work . i tried git pull origin master after checking the branches via git branch but that doesn't work either","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"what set of commands did you use to setup your public repository on your local machine did you initialise a new repo locally or push an existing repo.","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"i typed in git init and then git remote add origin ssh url .","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"you may have forgotten to do gt git push -u origin master on setup which would have linked your local to remote.","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thank you so much","theta":1,"count":0}]]]]]]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"tuts and labs","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"week 01","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"tutorial 01 - introduction to git and python basics","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"my education pack didn't come through so i tried to set up my own git repository. when i tried however it came up with this error message im not sure what to do exactly to fix this.","answers":[{"text":"hi ewan you must first turn your directory/folder into a git repository using 'git init' before you can do 'git remote add ...' - just as angla has said thank you angela . please try it and please let me know if it still does not solve the problem. d","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"try typing git init before you type git remote add .... it fixed the problem for me but idk if that's what we're supposed to do","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"tuts and labs","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"week 01","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"tutorial 01 - introduction to git and python basics","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"my github education discount pack was rejected and i'm unsure if i'm entering my details correctly or not so i clicked on 'student' and 'individual account'. then for name i entered my full name that appears on my student id. i then used my zid student.unsw.edu.au account that has been verified. school name unsw graduation year 2018 my reason was copied and pasted i will use github to work on group projects and as the version control tool for my coursework.","answers":[{"text":"hi cattleya the lab01 faq page has been released so please have a look at it and see if you can resolve your issues. if you are still having issues after following the faq page or if you are not too sure on how to follow the instructions listed please let me know. cheers ian","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"i got the same problem and i've got replied from github staff. i'm not so sure but it may be a quick solution","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"try uploading your id card or your academic transcript like it says in the box i think a real person will check it and then give you the educational discount. let me know if it works.","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"i used a photo of my id card and the request was accepted. thank you for all the suggestions and help.","theta":1,"count":0}]],{"text":"make sure your graduation year is correct. if it is 2018 then you will be out of unsw by the end of 2018 and into the workforce implying that you are in your final year of study . also i think your email should be zid ad.unsw.edu.au or zid cse.unsw.edu.au rather than zid student.unsw.edu.au. although i'm not sure myself as i got my education pack a long time ago. and as always make sure your details are correct. but other than that i can't really help i suggest asking your tutor or maybe aarthi today during the lecture break.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"i had the same thing happen to me not sure what to do.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"tuts and labs","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"week 01","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"tutorial 01 - introduction to git and python basics","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"do we need to use our github username on name field during github edu pack application i put my real name and i got rejected twice with my unsw.edu.au and student.unsw.edu.au email .","answers":[{"text":"thank you kevin for sharing your great solution to the issue","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"i think it is your real name. did you get some sort of email saying that github is trying to verify you and that they need a picture of your academic transcript or student id card","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"nevermind i already got my pack. i had to verify using cse.unsw.edu.au email to be approved","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"tuts and labs","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"week 01","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"tutorial 01 - introduction to git and python basics","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"my github education account has been denied 3 times for some reason. my last two requests got denied instantly i received a disapproving email straight after submitting my application . i applied with my real name and student email zid student.unsw.edu.au do i also need to upload student affiliation thanks","answers":[{"text":"hi shangjie the faq page has been released now - please go an have a look at possible ways to resolve your issue. however if you still cannot resolve your issue after going through the faq please let us know asa . thanks ian","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"use zid cse.unsw.edu.au email refer to thread https //webcms3.cse.unsw.edu.au/comp1531/18s2/foru... if your lab is coming up or has already past just use a public repo and make it private later.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"tuts and labs","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"week 01","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"tutorial 01 - introduction to git and python basics","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"i have committed and pushed the files but how could i check whether it is submitted successfully ps i checked the comp lab check it shows that i have not submitted week01 lab exercise. however i pushed them yesterday.","answers":[{"text":"hi jiahao please kindly note that we are not using give for the lab submissions in this course - instead you only need to push your work to github by the upcoming sunday 11.59pm. then in the first hours of next week's lab you may show your work to your tutor and get it marked off - so no need to use give and no need to check on give - just github. cheers ian","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"am i correct in saying the that you committed and pushed the files onto your repo if that is the case then you wouldn't have submitted. usually you can submit using the give command on the terminal. i'm not so sure what you mean by submitted successfully as far as i am aware you have to show your tutor that you have done the work then he/she will give you a grade. i didn't even know that there is a comp lab check mind if you give out the link because i can't find it.","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"i did not finish it in the lab because i just got the student pack a few minutes before the lab ended. here is the link of comp lab check https //cgi.cse.unsw.edu.au/ give/code/login.php app / give/student/sturec.php amp debug abort/get_authuser .","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thanks for the link yes this does look familiar. check this with your tutor but i think you have to show your tutor the work that you have done and then he will be the one who submits a mark out of 10 for your lab which you can later see.","theta":1,"count":0}]]]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"tuts and labs","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"week 01","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"tutorial 01 - introduction to git and python basics","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"my lab is this afternoon but i haven't got my github education account approved does it mean i won't be able to do the lab","answers":[{"text":"it's only the lab import that cannot be done. you should still be able to do the python exercises locally you could also just use a public repo for the moment and test all the git commands. once github education is approved then you could do import lab01 code and push your changes to the repo.","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"oh ok it's not too bad then. btw is there any help session this week thanks","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"there are consultations every week from 2.30 to 4 room 203 level 2 k17 every thursday.","theta":1,"count":0}]],{"text":"my tutor told me i should leave after reading through the lab thoroughly as you can't really access the labs tab of https //cgi.cse.unsw.edu.au/ cs1531/github/run.cgi/ without an education account","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"oh i guess you can just create a public repo for now and follow the lab instructions instead of actually click and go into the lab page","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"tuts and labs","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"week 01","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"tutorial 01 - introduction to git and python basics","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"some people have had their github education discount approved after five minutes and for others including me it's taking much longer. is there anything i could potentially be doing wrong that is delaying the process or is the approval time variation random and i should just wait a few more days","answers":[{"text":"the approval time-period is really random generally it comes through within 48 hours. if it has been more than 72 hours the i suggest that you reapply. but meanwhile you can do the python exercises locally and use a public repo and test the various git features.","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"okay thank you","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"tuts and labs","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"week 01","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"tutorial 01 - introduction to git and python basics","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"why does the github authorisation for the 1531 organisation require read and write access as well as delete access i have multiple private forked repositories that are to be maintained as secret where i work and i can't allow outside access to these as per nda's and various other sources of legal mumbo jumbo. i have already previous used my unsw email to give me the 'student pack' under my main account and so it is not as easy as just making another account for unsw usage my biggest concern is that i have a lab tomorrow so sorry for this inconvenience . edit it has come to my attention that from our side we can limit the scope i.e. https //github.com/login/oauth/authorize client_id... which limits it to only public data is that acceptable edit 2 i have resolved the problem by creating an account primarily for uni purposes which can also use the student pack under the alias i hope this is sufficient .","answers":[{"text":"hi braedon thank you so much for raising your sincere concerns about the 1531's oauthapp the github app and helping us improve the learning experience for the students of comp1531. also we really appreciate your sharing with us about how you resolved the problem. but to eliminate such privacy concerns for other and future students we have decided to modify the app to limit its access levels. please kindly note that currently no staffs of comp1531 has read/write access to your repos except for those repos created under the organisation. however once again we will further investigate the problem to definitely ensure that no breach of privacy could ever occur through the app. if you have any other concerns or issues please let us know d thanks ian park","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"we will only need the delete scope if you want full functionality of the class manager. occasionally there will be times where students will need to delete their working repo and refork the lab to start fresh. we wish to make it seamless for students new to git and github. feel free to limit the scope if you are comfortable with github and won't be needing this feature also feel free to make another account specifically for unsw if you find that appropriate as many others have done so to not mix up repos.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"can i second this - i also have projects i host that i can't share under such a broad agreement. edit re limiting scope i don't even think i could do that because i don't have transparency on whether that actually changes the content of the oauth request and it's kind of hacky at best.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"tuts and labs","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"week 01","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"tutorial 01 - introduction to git and python basics","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"so the tutorial asks to make a new repository and set it to private. setting to private costs money and i am poor. can i keep it public","answers":[{"text":"one of the instructions in the lab setup tasks asks you to request for github education account this will give you unlimited private repositories","theta":1,"count":0}]}]}